Yeah. That dress
really is perfect, isn't it?
Mm.
Ichito, don't you agree?
Your mother always looks
so beautiful in white.
She's been like this
for several years now.
The odds of her regaining consciousness,
are pretty low, right?
Right.
Unfortunately, what happened was
the blood flow to her brain was cut off,
causing severe damage.
And, sadly,
we aren't expecting any improvement.
Use the call button
if you need help with anything.
I, uh…
…wish I'd come to see her sooner.
It wouldn't have mattered.
Professor Toyohara.
I never thought you'd come here.
I got careless.
Professor, why are you here?
Your father and I were best friends,
back in university.
But slowly, we drifted apart.
Believe it or not,
I even changed your diaper.
After that whole thing happened,
I'd come back
to check on your mom occasionally.
So why…
didn't you ever tell me anything?
Because I knew very well
that you were avoiding your mother.
I thought having someone around
who knew what you'd been through
would be particularly painful.
I've been extremely hard on you,
and I'm sorry.
I wanted you to be able to move forward,
and I was hoping a sex therapist was
the last thing you'd want to be.
I realize how selfish that was.
It was almost as if
time had stood still.
In my memories,
my mother hadn't changed a bit.
Like she was still right there,
in that house.
Your mother…
has no recollection of what happened.
Really?
Likely a dissociative disorder.
I would venture to say that
time has completely frozen for her.
Before she lost consciousness,
she would go on and on
about the day your voice changed.
Or the time you made her
an omelette for Mother's Day.
I was wondering…
Professor, do you have…
any idea…
how something like this
could have happened?
I can't be sure.
But, uh…
I did, on occasion,
witness the sort of oppression
she was dealing with.
Oppression?
Ichito, your father
was quite a gifted surgeon.
He was also the definition
of a perfectionist.
And he expected that kind of perfection…
from all those around him,
including your mother.
He transformed her into a…
into a beautiful woman.
And what he believed was
the perfect wife and devoted mother.
Everything from
the clothes she wore,
right down to how she styled her hair.
That dress really is the perfect one.
Hm.
Enduring that kind of control
and oppression drove her to the brink.
And she had an affair,
just to escape it all.
That sent him into an absolute rage.
But his anger wasn't directed at her.
She was just the doll he had created.
It was focused on the man that…
had taken that doll away from him.
My father had
a Pygmalion complex.
At least, it seems that way.
A Pyg-malion complex?
Basically, what that is
is an obsession with dolls.
But, more specifically,
it's a desire to force another person
into an ideal mold and control them.
This whole time,
I thought my mother was
the one with sexual issues.
But, uh…
looks like it was my father
all along who was
the one with the problem.
These eerily named "Ghost Stairs"
are believed to have 40 steps going up,
but only 39 going down.
When you physically walk down,
there is a noticeable tilt
on that last step.
So you're saying there is
an obvious tilt on that last step, right?
All right, could you actually
climb those stairs again
so our viewers could see it live?
And…
Yumi?
Yes?
Everything okay? You need a break?
- Oh, no, I'm fine.
- Ah.
Ms. Ichinose. Morning.
Talk to you a minute?
Future Women Leaders Week?
Mmm.
The program directors
have developed this project
in order to modernize
the network's outdated corporate image.
The aim is to run several different
week-long special programs.
And our show is getting pulled
along for the ride.
I know it's looking pretty sparse
at first glance.
Think you and Mitarai can run wiEth it
and come up with a few ideas?
Hmm?
Is this for real?
Are you serious?
Ha. That's why I'm asking.
Get to it.
Uh, sir?
Why'd you ask me?
Hm.
Little bird told me
you were the one for the job.
Good luck!
Morning. Have a good vacation?
Hey! Shun, wait up.
Hey.
You recommended me
for the article, didn't you?
I really do appreciate it!
Huh?
Future Women Leaders Week.
Oh. You're gonna be working on that too?
Uh… Yes.
- Fantastic.
- Ah.
Well, if you need anything,
let me know, all right?
The reason why I asked you
why you chose to deal with sexuality
was out of genuine concern.
Is the work you do now…
actually a profession that you pursued
because you genuinely wanted to?
Doctor?
- Can I talk to you?
- Oh.
Things are getting a bit
out of hand out there.
- Huh?
- Can you have a look?
Thanks.
You see?
Uh… what exactly are you up to?
I figured, since we have no appointments,
I might as well get started
on some dried herbs.
Oh.
Could you bundle a few together for me?
- Three or four stems each.
- Uh… Yeah, sure.
And, Yuta… you get…
Huh?
This!
What's this?
Oh!
These smell great.
Yeah.
Herbs keep their fragrance for a while,
even after they've been cut.
Argh! A bug!
The scent is so vibrant
when they're nice and fresh.
Then it becomes more mellow
and concentrated when they're dry.
- Oh! Another bug!
- You're ruining the mood!
Just try to… keep it down.
All right?
Sorry.
The fragrance of a flower
will remain in your mind
long after its beauty has wilted.
Hello?
- Ah!
Hi, is it possible to see the doctor,
even if I don't have an appointment?
- Oh. Yes.
- Thank you.
Hello.
I… uh…
I attended your lectures
at the university a while ago.
Oh.
Yuka Namioka.
Yes.
So, how can I help you, Yuka?
It's probably nothing.
And if anyone told me this really wasn't
worth pursuing, I'd most likely drop it.
If this is something
that's bothering you, Yuka,
then it's worth pursuing.
There's a professor,
at the university.
The way he looks at me,
it just feels very sexual.
Maybe I'm imagining it, I… I don't know.
Why don't you tell me a little more?
Well, seeing as though
I'm an undergrad student,
I spend a lot of time in the lab
working on projects
in the field I want to specialize in.
This professor was quite easy to talk to.
Suddenly, he started taking
a real interest in my research.
Or specifically, an interest in me.
Oh… That sounded really conceited,
didn't it?
I just meant, you know…
Ah.
Then he started inviting me to faculty
dinners and events and things like that.
I was happy about it at first, I admit.
But eventually,
the outings and dinners were more private.
Then there were overnight conferences.
And I was the only one he invited.
He never made any physical advances,
and it's not like he asked me
to share a hotel room or anything.
That's why I never felt like
I could tell anyone anything about it.
But it made you feel uncomfortable,
or that he might have wanted you sexually?
And when we were, um…
at those conferences,
it always felt like…
more of a couple thing
than student-professor.
It kind of made me feel like an escort.
He even bought me clothes
to wear to all these things.
He'd also invite me to these dessert bars.
He said, as an older man,
he felt funny going there alone.
A bizarre man this, uh…
Professor Kurusu.
What do you think of this?
Hmm…
- Think they'll approve it?
- Not sure.
I don't know if it has the hook
Kujo is always looking for.
Yeah, I know.
Hey, uh…
Sorry for keeping you here so late.
It's okay. Look, it's a good idea, though.
I think you need to become the kind of
journalist you've always wanted to be.
I remember, back in school,
I always thought you'd make
an amazing field reporter.
You thought that?
Aww! Thank you!
I'm so happy to be working with you!
So tell me…
You were the one who recommended me
for this project, weren't you?
I really appreciate it.
No. It wasn't me.
Huh?
- Huh?
Japan lags far behind in sex education,
and the public's ignorance is
the driving force behind this proposal.
Hmm.
Mm. Feels like it's a bit heavy.
To be clear, I'm not against airing this.
It just needs more of a hook.
- Right.
- Uh… yeah.
- Mm.
- Hm.
Japan ranks especially low
on the Gender Gap Index,
so how about we focus more
on the lack of political participation?
Mm-mm. Mm, no. That's the kind of thing
News One covers
in their 10:00 p.m. segment.
We're an evening news show.
I want to take a more casual approach.
- Okay? Harashima!
- Right. Sorry.
- All good.
- Okay, then…
Does anyone here know what
the Pygmalion complex is?
Pyg-what?
I just actually learned about it myself.
It refers to people, mostly men,
who treat their women like dolls.
Who try to mold them into
their idea of perfection.
Ironically, where I'm concerned,
I feel like this company and our viewers
have been doing exactly that to me.
But I don't think it's necessarily
because I'm a female TV personality.
I think it expands to almost any woman
out there living in this country today.
This society forces expectations
of womanhood onto us.
It robs all women,
and makes us feel like dolls.
- It's especially prevalent with sex--
- Miss Ichinose.
Again, I find that way too serious.
- I agree.
- I just don't know anymore.
- So what's the consensus?
- Wait a minute.
You're saying this will involve
women openly discussing sex?
Yes. Yes, exactly. Exactly right.
I want us to take this opportunity
to tackle the topic of sex head-on.
That's pretty gutsy, I got to admit.
A special feature like this
coming from a female reporter,
I mean, that's exactly
what we're looking for, isn't it?
- It'll be different.
- A welcome change.
From the light, gossipy stuff
we did in the past.
- Sure.
- Don't you think?
- Uh, whew… Let's go for it.
- Definitely has a hook.
- Give it a shot!
- Really?
- Oh, yeah?
- So what do we call it? Anyone?
Any ideas?
How does "So You Want
To Talk About Sex?" sound?
- Catchy!
- I like it.
- Oh, yeah. Great!
- Mitarai.
- Yes.
- You and Miss Ichinose get working on it.
On it.
I'll make sure it's green-lit upstairs.
- All right, let's get to it.
- Great.
- Amazing.
- I'm excited.
- Great!
- You heard the man!
This was all your doing, wasn't it?
Recommending me?
Hmm.
Thank you.
Don't thank me.
I just wanted to make the show better.
Yumi, do you remember
the time you and I got an invite
to entertain a sponsor?
Huh?
One of the clients got drunk that night.
He started harassing us
at the karaoke after-party.
Aah.
You discreetly stepped in and diverted
his attention away from me, didn't you?
Just so I wouldn't be the target.
Mmm.
Yeah, I remember.
I was, uh…
really pissed off at you.
Huh?
I wanted you to actually say something.
Not just play the victim
and take one for the team.
I wanted you to step up.
And while we're at it,
female TV personalities should be
free to date whoever they want.
Why should some old scandal
about a boyfriend's parents
affect how a woman on TV is judged?
I hated seeing you bow to the pressure
and go along with
whatever they expected of you.
Uh…
is this funny?
Uh. No. My bad.
Hey.
Let's have dinner.
What? So now
you're trying to be my best friend?
I'm serious. Let's have dinner.
Do you like Italian?
- Rolling.
- Hello, excuse me.
We're asking people today if they have any
concerns related to sex. How about you?
And so I've tried to find a partner
on several dating apps.
I apologize, I know it can be awkward
talking about sex. How do you feel about…
…about the lack of openness
when it comes to sex?
- Are you asking in public?
- That's personal!
I gotta tell you, I really didn't think
anyone would be willing to talk to us,
but people had way more to say
than I ever could've imagined.
Mmm.
My wife and I don't have sex anymore.
Now I'm thinking it might have
something to do with me.
Don't know if that's true.
But sexual issues can affect men
as well as women.
Hm.
If people have as many
concerns as we think,
we should have a professional
talk about it.
Mmm.
We just gotta find someone
we could interview.
- Oh! What about Furuya?
- Imagine that!
- I don't think so.
- No, then?
Then he said he wanted
to do it without a condom.
What about STDs or getting
pregnant? Does that concern you?
- Yes, it totally does.
- I don't blame you.
My husband and I haven't
had sex in well over two years now,
and so I've tried to find a partner
on several different dating apps.
- You don't mind multiple partners?
- Okay.
As long as I'm--
Think it's time to take a little break.
Yes.
- We're just taking a quick break.
- Yeah, of course.
Oh.
How's it going?
- Oh, thanks.
- No problem.
Well, the footage is looking good.
Trouble is, we're having
a problem finding a commentator.
Yeah, I can see how
that could be a challenge.
Yumi?
Mind if I ask you something?
Sure.
What kind of relationship
do you have with Shun?
What?
Relationship? We're co-workers.
He's senior and I'm junior.
That's not what I mean.
What I'm asking is
what you think of him as a man?
Uh…
Um… is it possible
that you're interested in him?
Oh, goodness, no. Not at all.
- I didn't think so.
- Right.
But haven't the two of you
gone for a meal together?
Yeah. That was really
only a work thing, though.
Wait.
Are you saying that he…
That's exactly what I'm saying.
Shun definitely has feelings for you.
Oh, man…
I… I, uh…
- I sure hope not.
- I know, right?
You don't think he'd take advantage
of his position, do you?
I can't believe he'd use
his seniority like that.
- Think that's what he's doing?
- You never know.
Guys like that would stoop to any means
if they thought it could get them
somewhere with a woman.
All I know is that I'm so thankful
that kind of drama isn't happening
on my own show.
But I have to admit…
I wasn't sure what was
going on between the two of you.
- Well, let me put that to rest.
- Good!
Nothing at all.
Oh, I can't tell you
how relieved I am. Seriously!
I told you, it's just a misunderstanding!
Don't tell me she's saying it's some
kind of sexual or academic harassment?
No.
- But you have--
- Just listen.
She was under no obligation to come.
I never forced her or pressured her.
You have to admit, as a student,
there are benefits
to attending a conference.
And you are clearly
in an influential position as a professor.
If she says no to having lunch,
or doesn't accept a gift,
she'd be worried that
she was upsetting her professor.
And that kind of concern could
already be considered
harassment.
Hmm.
- That girl really didn't seem the type--
- It's not "that girl."
Her name's Yuka Namioka.
Wouldn't you agree
you were putting your own feelings
and assumptions ahead of Yuka's?
Can you not see why this would
put her in an awkward position?
And by doing that,
can you not see you were treating her
like your own personal doll?
My father did that exact thing.
He never considered my mother's feelings.
He insisted on pushing
his ideal image on her.
And because of that,
my mother suffered terribly.
The whole time they were together.
All right, but that has nothing
to do with me, though.
No.
It doesn't, but back then,
there was really nothing I could do.
But now…
Now I know I have the opportunity to help
someone else in the same situation.
You can make things right.
It's not too late.
Why not give therapy a shot?
I know I can help you.
Ah. You give me no choice.
I could never say no to you.
Thank you. You won't regret this.
Hello, Yumi? It's me.
Hi.
So, uh…
I need to tell you something.
So, uh, how's your mom doing?
She seems stable, thanks for asking.
But she still hasn't regained
consciousness at all.
I'm sorry.
So I, uh…
I wanted to tell you something,
but now, uh…
I'm having trouble
finding the words to say it.
Don't worry. Take your time.
As soon as you feel like talking,
I'm listening.
Hmm.
So I, um…
I chose to pursue this profession
as a means of making up for…
for shunning my parents.
So, there it is.
Professor Toyohara asked me,
"Are you doing this job because you want
to, or because you feel you have to?"
Even if it was for redemption,
it's still amazing that so many people
got help because of you.
That's why…
I've thought it over
and I want to choose again.
Except this time, I wanna choose it
because I really want to do it.
Not as a means of redemption.
But commit to it.
To all those people.
And to my parents.
And also to myself.
I think Marin said it best.
The fragrance of a flower
will remain in your mind
long after its beauty has wilted.
Hmm.
Can I ask you something now, Ichito?
I, uh…
I would really love
for you to be on my show.
What?
Turns out, uh…
sex is pretty hard to discuss.
And there are so many people out there
who have no one to listen to them.
But, uh…
There are people like you, Ichito,
who will listen to their problems
and try to help.
And they should know that.
Will you come on the show?
So tell me, how's he doing now?
Ask him yourself.
You don't need to go through me anymore.
Now that everything's out in the open.
It's not that simple.
He won't open up to me now.
Funny, but I seem to remember you dumping
him on me and asking if I could help him.
You didn't mind being
the bad guy for that.
You were having fun with it too.
Of course I was.
I got to have a front-row
seat to a romance reality show.
Who wouldn't want that?
Stay tuned for a CTV special.
- Tomorrow, only on Central Television.
- Think he can put this behind him?
- Don't miss Twilight News at 4:45 p.m.
- Just her mere existence…
- The special "Future Women Leaders."
- A reason to face his past, move forward.
The first guest will be sex therapist
Dr. Ichito Shimotori.
We'll be discussing sexual issues
that are often hard to talk about.
- At 7:00 p.m…
- Boy, Yumi really went for it, huh?
…young women zookeepers
that are leading us into the future.
We'll also take a look at the incredible
behaviour of some of these animals.
I just got the results
of my annual physical.
- Oh, yeah?
- There were a couple of issues.
- Oh! Everything okay?
- Yeah, yeah I'm fine.
- Ah.
- But I still have to be careful.
- We gotta take care of ourselves.
- Yeah.
And, after the commercial break,
we'll have the first in the series
"Future Women Leaders".
And we're out.
Dr. Shimotori is arriving on set.
Listen.
No matter what, I'm right here.
I can see you're ready.
I'm a pro, after all.
- Mind if I mic you now?
- Sure.
Back in five,
four, three,
two…
Next up is our special of the week,
"Future Women Leaders."
Tell us, Yumi, what is the theme tonight?
Right.
Tonight on Twilight News we have
sexual issues that women
may be dealing with.
They may be future leaders but they
still need a bit of help sometimes.
Well, that is
a pretty bold topic, isn't it?
Sexual issues have always…
been considered somewhat obscene,
or embarrassing for some reason.
But in Japan, it's a real issue,
due to the lack of sex education
in our society.
I believe it's necessary
to create a more open dialogue
where we can discuss these topics
in a more relaxed and welcoming way.
Thanks, Yumi.
To start, let's have a look at this.
- We'd like to talk about sexual issues.
- Clip rolling.
- This way, doctor.
- Thanks.
- Right here.
- Thank you.
Hello.
- What about…
- Okay!
The guy we've all been waiting for!
I'm still surprised you're doing this.
Yeah, well, you don't get a chance
to pull in these numbers every day!
I had to convince the higher-ups
to get this on the air.
And we're back in five,
four, three, two…
So… after all these interviews,
it was obvious to me that there
are many people out there
who have sexual issues
and no one to talk to.
What you've seen is only a small sample
of what people are going through.
I had no idea there were so many
people dealing with these concerns.
It's really eye-opening.
So today, we have
a psychiatrist and sex therapist
who is certified by the American
Association of Sexual Educators.
Dr. Ichito Shimotori joins us
to discuss this ever-growing trend.
Dr. Shimotori, thank you for being here.
Thanks for having me.
Dr. Shimotori,
we've heard that you've treated,
um… many people at your clinic.
Can you tell us a little bit about that?
Yes.
Even the term "sex therapy"
isn't something most
of our viewers are familiar with.
Can you explain what kind
of treatment you perform?
Sure.
But first, uh…
allow me to, uh tell you
just a little bit about myself.
I'm sure your audience is curious
to hear my background, right?
I imagine many of you
have read the tabloids.
You've learned that my…
my father committed…
assault 17 years ago
against my mother's lover.
Just keep rolling.
Stay on him.
I'll admit that…
that incident had a major impact
on my decision
to become a sex therapist today.
And so…
I firmly believe that if sex therapy
was available all those years ago,
that might not have happened.
And my parents may not have
suffered the way they did.
Hang in there!
Hmm.
But of course,
none of us can change the past.
But what I'm hoping to do today
is listen to what people have to say
with a clear and open mind.
And I hope that
I'll be able to help people like
my mother avoid painful experiences
through sexual education.
But there's also others out there,
people like my father,
with different issues,
who hurt others,
and I want to help them too.
Thank you, Dr. Shimotori.
On today's show, we'll be focusing
on some of the more common concerns
that we encountered through
these interviews.
And with the doctor's help,
shed some light on these issues.
Good.
First up, we have this.
It's not helpful to blame your partner
if they're not making you feel loved.
What you need is to sit down
and have a meaningful conversation
that will help you understand each other.
- Aah! This guy is so great!
- Another popular issue…
- Ooh! Yeah!
- …to use contraception.
Often, you're so focused
on what your partner likes,
that you end up doing whatever they want
without thinking of your own needs.
So either partner
should feel comfortable saying no.
There's also an option
that lands somewhere
between self-pleasure
and sex with a partner.
I discovered recently that
virtual sex can be helpful to some.
In the end, it is very healthy
to explore all options
and to arrive at a place that is
sexually satisfying for everyone.
Another common concern was this.
"Why is female masturbation
considered so taboo?"
Are women expected to refrain?
I was once told something,
and I've been thinking about
it ever since then.
There is nothing wrong
with making yourself feel good.
There's a reason
it's called "self-pleasure".
So why not just simply
consider it pleasing yourself?
I fully admit to pleasing myself.
It's not something
we should feel embarrassed by.
I definitely do it fairly often.
That's not abnormal, is it, doctor?
No, of course it's not.
For instance, I have a patient
who was concerned
because they were doing it so frequently.
Often enough that they couldn't
focus on their work and…
They have to realize it's no bad thing.
- This guy's talking about me!
- The most…
I don't believe it, listen to this!
- Hah!
- What?
Hey, guys, come over here!
Look, he's talking about me!
Just to recap, so far,
we've been discussing sexual issues
that women find difficult
to discuss with anyone.
- Doctor…
- It's trending! It's trending!
- …not only women…
- We're number one!
- Not now! I don't wanna miss this part.
- Absolutely.
And I know this may sound simple,
but just listen to each other.
We have to be honest
with each other and share our feelings.
I really believe that
it's the most effective way
of resolving any issues that come up.
It's true.
I guess we never really know
what people think of us, do we?
Unless we just come right out
and ask them.
Exactly.
I get that.
I've just recently
experienced that myself.
It's nothing serious, I hope?
Well…
Not really. Uh…
Doctor,
any final words to leave us with?
Yes.
Just know that
sex is not only
for the sole purpose of reproduction.
Sexual intimacy takes
many different forms in today's world.
It's not so cut and dry anymore.
It's become more complex.
Problems can vary,
depending on the individual.
And quite often,
someone can feel trapped
and have no one to turn to.
But before that happens,
I believe there's something I can do.
People.
Don't hide and stay quiet anymore.
Talk to someone.
Discuss your sexual issues.
Just know that
when it comes to sex, no one is sure
about anything.
KAWAWA SHRINE
LANTERN FESTIVAL
Here we are.
Oh, wow.
- Wow is right.
- It's beautiful.
- It really is.
- Mmm.
It's just so magical.
You're right, it's gorgeous.
It feels like it's finally moving again.
What is?
My inner clock that stopped 17 years ago.
Glad to hear it.
I wanna thank you.
For listening to me. All this time.
I wanna thank you as well.
Because you also listened to me.